# Muhammad Faizan

# App Developer (Native Android + Flutter)

Islamabad

mohammadfaizan980@gmail.com

+92 341 9299464

An app developer and a designer with 3 years of development experience. I work in both, Native Android (Kotlin) and Flutter App Development. In native android development, I use jetpack compose instead of XML.

I have tendency to learn and adapt new things quickly. For example, I learned Node.js when I needed to work on some APIs, learned Figma when needed to demonstrate a UI concept with prototype, learned Strapi when a project required me for that, learned SDUI when a project needed and many more examples.

# Work Experience

### App Developer (Flutter + Kotlin)

Safarifone - Islamabad February 2022 to Present

Currently working here as a full time app developer, working a native android app using jetpack compose, app will connect with vending machines for providing POS services using serial communication with the vending machine and also raspberryPi connection for machines which do not allow direct communication with internal hardware. Along with that, I am also working on a flutter app for the hosts, who will provide their property for hosting the vending machine for public use. Also sometimes doing UI/UX designing and prototyping.

#### **Flutter Developer**

Tentwenty Digital - Islamabad March 2021 to February 2022

Worked here as a full time flutter app developer with periodic backend work for APIs development with Node js

# Flutter/Android Developer

Infusible Coders - Kohat February 2019 to March 2021

Worked here as native android and flutter app developer and worked on variety of apps mainly using google maps, InApp payments, stripe, REST APIs, Firebase services.

#### Education

#### **BSCS**

Kohat University of Science and Technology 2016 to 2020

### Skills

- Flutter
- Kotlin
- Java
- Dart
- MVVM
- Providers
- Rest APIs
- Stacked
- Location Services
- Sockets
- Bluetooth Communication
- Firebase (storage, auth, social auth, firestore, realtime DB)
- · Google Maps
- Leaflet.js Maps aka Flutter Map
- SDUI

### Languages

- Urdu Expert
- English Intermediate

# Links

https://muhammadfaizan980.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/faizan-%F0%9F%93%B1-senior-flutter-developer-5054aa164

# Additional Information

Following is an abstract list of highlighted apps I have worked with:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tentwenty.whocares Whocares allows people to stay in touch with your loved ones. You can update your status, create your spaces and invite people via link, you can ask a person for their status and more.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.thampy.dfsa
Official DFSA app to stay in touch with their news and announcements and enquiry.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apps.brainer\_book App to help train your brain and improve your memory. https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mgks.os.jumpi South African govt app for entrepreneurs and to help them in their journey by keeping them in engaged with via podcasts and more.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aramco.saudi.pavilion Saudi Pavilion management app for Dubai Expo 2020 for VIP management.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apps.amass
An app for keeping your brain healthy, you can create your classes, add items to them, keep track of your progress and so on.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.org.lsuk Employees management app for LSUK (UK based company)